theeventscalendar.com 2019-09-02

# Privacy Policy | The Events Calendar

Last updated: _August 10, 2017_

Modern Tribe, Inc. (“us”, “we”, or “our”) operates websites including but not limited to [https://theeventscalendar.com](https://theeventscalendar.com/) (collectively the “Websites”) where we offer premium code, data processing services, and support (collectively “Plugins”). Cumulatively all of our Plugins and our Websites constitute our “Service”. This page informs you of our policies regarding the collection, use and disclosure of Personal Information when you use our Service. We will not knowingly use or share your information with anyone except as described in this Privacy Policy. We use your Personal Information for providing and improving the Service. By using the Service, you agree to the collection and use of information in accordance with this policy. Unless otherwise defined in this Privacy Policy, terms used in this Privacy Policy have the same meanings as in our [Terms and Conditions](https://theeventscalendar.com/terms).

## Website Data Collection and Use

### Information Collection and Use

While using our Websites, we may ask you to provide us with certain personally identifiable information that can be used to contact or identify you. Personally identifiable information may include, but is not limited to, your email address, name, phone number, and/or other information (“Personal Information”). We collect this information for the purpose of providing the Websites, identifying and communicating with you, responding to your requests/inquiries, servicing your purchase orders, and improving our Service.

### Log Data

We may also collect information whenever you use our Websites (“Log Data”). This Log Data may include, but is not limited to information such as your computer’s Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, browser type, browser version, the pages of our Websites that you visit, the time and date of your visit, the time spent on those pages and other statistics.

In addition, we may use third party services such as Google Analytics that collect, monitor and analyze this type of information in order to increase our Websites’ functionality. These third party service providers have their own privacy policies addressing how they use such information.

### Cookies

Cookies are files with a small amount of data, which may include an anonymous unique identifier. Cookies are sent to your browser from a web site and transferred to your device. We use cookies to collect information in order to improve our Websites for you. You can instruct your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. The Help feature on most browsers provide information on how to accept cookies, disable cookies or to notify you when receiving a new cookie. If you do not accept cookies, you may not be able to use some features of our Websites and we recommend that you leave them turned on.

### Behavioral Remarketing

Modern Tribe, Inc. uses remarketing services to advertise on third party web sites to you after you visited our Websites. We, and our third party vendors, use cookies to inform, optimize and serve ads based on your past visits to our Websites.

#### AdRoll

AdRoll remarketing service is provided by Semantic Sugar, Inc. You can opt-out of AdRoll remarketing by visiting this [AdRoll Advertising Preferences web page](http://info.evidon.com/pub_info/573?v=1&nt=1&nw=false). For more information on the privacy practices of AdRoll, please visit the [AdRoll Privacy Policy](http://www.adroll.com/about/privacy)

## Plugin Data Collection and Use

### Default Information Collection and Use

We collect data through the use or our premium Plugins to provide updates and support. By default we collect the minimum necessary information about the website where the Plugin is installed including:

  * IP address
  * Domain name
  * Our plugin version and license key
  * WordPress version
  * Is the site a multisite install and if so, how many sites are there and is the Plugin installed singularly or across the network?
  * Site language and timezone
  * Public and debug statuses

This information is reported in the processes for checking for plugin updates or interacting with our data processing services.

### Opt-In Information Collection and Use

In addition to the default data collection, we may ask for permission to collect additional “opt-in” data for the purposes of helping you debug in support tickets or to personalizing your Plugin usage experience as well as improving our Plugins in general. This information may include but is not limited to the following:

  * More granular system compatibility information including PHP and mysql version
  * Information about what other plugins and what theme is running on the system so that we may better identify where to invest resources into compatibility testing
  * Relevant settings and configurations
  * Content statistics such as number of events or number of events with tickets
  * System events such as date of first event creation

We may also ask for permission to collect information in our free Plugins. Your consent will also permit us to collect your name and email for the purposes of communication.

You may, at any time, toggle your information sharing status in the Plugin settings. For more information, see [these instructions](https://theeventscalendar.com/knowledgebase/sharing-sys-info/).

### Event Aggregator Information Collection and Use

Our Event Aggregator data processing service collects and processes event information for your event imports. A cache of that data is temporarily stored on the server for up to 24 hours for performance purposes. A history of event import types and anonymized statistical information is stored for the purposes of improving our service and anticipating future demand.

## Service Providers

We may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate our Service, to provide the Service on our behalf, to perform related services and/or to assist us in analyzing how our Service is used. For example, we share cookies with trusted third parties, in order to supply our Help Desk Support. These third parties have access to your Personal Information only to perform specific tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use your information for any other purpose.

## Communications

We may use your Personal Information to contact you with newsletters, marketing or promotional materials and other information that may be of interest to you. You may opt out of receiving any, or all, of these communications from us by following the unsubscribe link or instructions provided in any email we send.

## Compliance with Laws

We will disclose your Personal Information where required to do so by law or subpoena or if we believe that such action is necessary to comply with the law and the reasonable requests of law enforcement or to protect the security or integrity of our Service.

To execute a Data Request, please do so [here](https://theeventscalendar.com/knowledgebase/modern-tribe-gdpr/).

## Security

The security of your Personal Information is important to us, and we strive to implement and maintain reasonable, commercially reasonable security procedures and practices appropriate to the nature of the information we store, in order to protect it from unauthorized access, destruction, use, modification, or disclosure.

Our credit card processing vendors are PCI compliant.

Website accounts require a username and password. Passwords are stored encrypted and not as “clear text” so that not even our employees can read it. We can not resend you your password, only reset it. For this reason, it is essential that you keep your password secure and never share it with a third party. **It is solely your responsibility to make sure that your password is strong, unique and private.**

We use industry-standard Secure Socket Layer (SSL) software to protect the security of your personal information during transmission, which encrypts all of the information you input. Only employees who need personal information to perform a specific job (for example, a customer service representative) are granted access to it. All of our employees are kept up to date on our privacy and security practices. Please be aware that no method of transmission over the internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure and we are unable to guarantee the absolute security of the Personal Information we have collected from you.

## International Transfer

Your information, including Personal Information, may be transferred to, and maintained on, computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the data protection laws may differ than those from your jurisdiction. Please note that we store and transfer all of our data, including Personal Information, to United States and process it there. Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.

## Links To Other Sites

Our Service may contain links to other sites that are not operated by us. If you click on a third party link, you will be directed to that third party’s site. We strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy of every site you visit. We have no control over, and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies or practices of any third party sites or services.

## Children’s Privacy

Only persons age 18 or older have permission to access our Service. Our Service does not address anyone under the age of 18 (“Children”). We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 18. If you are a parent or guardian and you learn that your Children have provided us with Personal Information, please contact us. If we become aware that we have collected Personal Information from children under age 18 without verification of parental consent, we take steps to remove that information from our servers.

## Venue and Choice of Law

This Privacy Policy is governed by and construed in accordance with the internal laws of the State of California without giving effect to any choice or conflict of law provision or rule. Any legal suit, action or proceeding arising out of or related to this Agreement or the Application shall be instituted exclusively in the courts of the State of California in each case located in Santa Cruz County. You waive any and all objections to the exercise of jurisdiction over you by such courts and to venue in such courts.

## Changes To This Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy is effective as of August 26, 2016 and will remain in effect except with respect to any changes in its provisions in the future, which will be in effect immediately after being posted on this page. We reserve the right to update or change our Privacy Policy at any time and you should check this Privacy Policy periodically. Your continued use of the Service after we post any modifications to the Privacy Policy on this page will constitute your acknowledgment of the modifications and your consent to abide and be bound by the modified Privacy Policy.

## Other Agreements

Nothing in this Privacy Policy shall modify any rights or obligations existing under the [Terms and Conditions](https://theeventscalendar.com/terms), or any other agreements between you and Modern Tribe, Inc.
